What we want to talk about is how to keep our receivers in a position to make an easy catch and be able to score for your team.
First, we have to run a good pattern.
After the guy runs a good pattern and gets open and the quarterback makes a good throw we have to make sure we make the catch.
I want to talk about one strategy of making a catch.
When the quarterback throws the ball at the chest or higher you have to go up and make the catch with your hands.
You cannot try to make a catch to the side with a cradle hand position.
If it's thrown over the top of you then you can cradle it behind you.
But, if it's thrown right to you, you have to go out with your hands.
You don't want to go get the ball because alot of times it you'll hit the ball and it will ricochet off your hands.
You want to catch it real soft into our hands and bring in to you.
Imagine this was made of glass and you're really trying to protect it.
You want to catch it and bring it in.
We're going to show you what it looks like when our receiver comes across and catches the ball chest high or above.
You can see he does a great job of getting his hands out, he doesn't go get the ball, he lets the ball come to him nice and soft, cradles it, turns it up field looking for the touchdown.